<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
Copyright (C) 2021 - Today: Magnus (http://www.magnus.nl)
@author: Vincent Verheul (v.verheul@magnus.nl)
License AGPL-3.0 or later (http://www.gnu.org/licenses/agpl.html).
-->

<odoo>
    <record id="save_addin_file_wizard_view" model="ir.ui.view">
        <field name="name">bi.sql.excel.addinfile.form</field>
        <field name="model">bi.sql.excel.addinfile.wizard</field>
        <field name="arch" type="xml">
            <form string="File download">
                <field name="has_data" invisible="1"/>
                <group cols="2" attrs="{'invisible': [('has_data', '=', True)]}">
                    <p>Click Prepare File first, then download the file to your computer</p>
                    <br/>
                    <button name="prepare_addin_file" string="Prepare File"
                            type="object" class="oe_highlight" icon="fa-arrow-right text-success"/>
                    <br/>
                </group>
                <group cols="2" attrs="{'invisible': [('has_data', '=', False)]}">
                    <field name="addin_file_name" invisible="1"/>
                    <field name="json_csv_win_file_name" invisible="1"/>
                    <field name="json_csv_mac_file_name" invisible="1"/>
                    <separator string="Add-in files ready for download" colspan="2"/>
                    <p colspan="2">Click to download. Choose Odoo-reports.xlam and select either the OdooJsonToCsvWin.exe (Windows)
                        or OdooJsonToCsvMac.exe (Apple Mac) version:</p>
                    <field name="addin_data" filename="addin_file_name" nolabel="1" colspan="2"/>
                    <field name="json_csv_win_data" filename="json_csv_win_file_name" nolabel="1" colspan="2"/>
                    <field name="json_csv_mac_data" filename="json_csv_mac_file_name" nolabel="1" colspan="2"/>
                    <br/><br/>
                    <separator string="Installing the Add-in" colspan="2"/>
                    <strong>Windows</strong>
                    <p colspan="2">
                        Save the files to your Downloads folder. Open the Properties of the
                        files and uncheck the <i>Blocked</i> indicator when it is set. Close Excel if it is opened.
                        Now move only the file Odoo-reports.xlam to a folder of choice or the official folder for Add-ins
                        C:\Users\&lt;username&gt;\AppData\Roaming\Microsoft\AddIns.
                        The AppData folder is a hidden folder. To make it visible in the File Explorer,
                        select View in the menu and enable the Hidden Items option.
                        Leave the .exe file in the Downloads folder.
                    </p>
                    <p colspan="2">
                        Start Excel when the Add-in file is in the designated folder.
                        In Excel choose File - Options - Add-ins. At the bottom you will
                        see 'Manage: Excel Add-ins'. Select 'Excel Add-ins' when not already selected and
                        click 'Go...'. You should see Odoo-Reports in the list (or use Browse...); select it to activate.
                        Now you should see an Odoo section in the ribbon (within 'Home').
                    </p>
                    <strong>Mac</strong>
                    <p colspan="2">
                        Save the files to your Downloads folder. Get the file info and uncheck the
                        <i>Locked</i> indicator when it is set. Then <strong>quit</strong> Excel.
                        Now move only the file Odoo-reports.xlam to a folder of choice or the official folder for Add-ins
                        /Users/&lt;username&gt;/Library/Group Containers/UBF8T346G9.Office/User Content/Add-ins.
                        Note that 'Library' and 'User Content' is language dependent. The Library folder (under Users)
                        is a hidden folder. To make it visible in the Finder, type Shift + Command + dot.
                        Use the 'Go' menu option and choose Computer, then Macintosh HD. Now you should see the
                        Users folder. Follow the path as descibed above. Leave the .exe file in the Downloads folder.
                    </p>
                    <p colspan="2">
                        Start Excel when the Add-in file is in the designated folder. In Excel choose Tools - Add-ins.
                        You should see Odoo-Reports in the list (or use Browse...); select it to activate.
                        Now you should see an Odoo section in the ribbon (within 'Home').
                    </p>
                    <strong>Odoo Json to CSV</strong>
                    <p colspan="2">
                        The OdooJsonToCsv executable is a tool to convert data received from Odoo (in Json format)
                        to a CSV format which can be loaded by Excel. It can do this much faster than the Excel Add-in itself.
                        Leave this file in the Downloads folder, the Add-in will pick it up from there.
                    </p>
                    <br/>
                    <separator string="Configure the Excel Add-in" colspan="2"/>
                    <p colspan="2">
                        In Excel, from the Odoo menu click <strong>Settings</strong>. Check the settings,
                        verify your username and enter your password. Click Test to validate and click OK to save.
                        Now click <strong>Get Index</strong> to get an overview of available reports. Select reports
                        by marking them in column B with a character (x for example). You may need to select the scope
                        for some reports, for example select the relevant projects when the report is about projects.
                        Then click <strong>Get Reports</strong> to get the reports which will appear on
                        separate worksheets.
                    </p>
                </group>
                <footer>
                    <button special="cancel" string="Cancel" type="object" icon="fa-times"
                        attrs="{'invisible': [('has_data', '=', True)]}"/>
                    <button special="cancel" string="OK" type="object"
                        attrs="{'invisible': [('has_data', '=', False)]}"/>
                </footer>
            </form>
        </field>
    </record>
</odoo>
